CURRICULUM VITAE

Xinlei Zhang

☐ +1 984-800-4198

xzhan245@ncsu.edu Personal Website

RESEARCH INTERESTS & GOAL

My research interests lie in the **theories** and **applications** in **robotics**, including **state estimation** & **system dynamics**, **nonlinear control**, and **data-driven methods**. My goal is to advance robotics research by integrating artificial intelligence and control theory methods.

EDUCATION

m North Carolina State University | Mechanical Engineering

Department of Aerospace and Mechanical Engineering

08/2024 - Present ♥ Raleigh, US

Department of Aerospace and Mechanical Engineering

09/2020 - 07/2024

■ South China University of Technology | Intelligent Manufacturing Shien-Ming Wu School of Intelligent Engineering

♀ Guangzhou, China

Overall GPA

3.78/4.00

Related Courses

- Applied Calculus II 96/100, Linear Algebra 97/100, Probability and Statistics 89/100
- Artificial Intelligence Technology and Applications 90/100, Data Structure 91/100
- Sensor Technology and Applications 90/100, Mechatronics 92/100
- System Dynamics 91/100, Classical Control Theory 92/10, Modern Control Theory 95/100

PUBLICATION & PATENT

On Ambiguity in 6-DoF Magnetic Pose Estimation & | First Author

Second-round Review

Xinlei Zhang, Shuda Dong, Yifeng Zeng and Heng Wang

Submitted to International Journal of Robotics Research (IJRR)

A Virtual Ultrasonography Simulator for Skill Training Using Magnetic-Inertial Probe Tracking Pending Heng Wang, Shuangyi Wang, Suqi Liu, Shuda Dong, Xinlei Zhang

Tieng wang, Shuangyi wang, Suqi Liu, Shuda Dong, Airiei z

Applied to CN Patent, No.CN116312122A &

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

The Lab of Magnetic-Controlled Robot, SCUT *Research Assistant*, advised by Prof. Heng Wang §

09/2021-07/2024

6-DoF Magnetic-Inertial Pose Estimation

09/2021-12/2021

• Contribution:

- * Debugged the magnetic-inertial sensor and sensor-arduino-Matlab communication.
- * Reviewed the literature regarding the magnetic-inertial pose estimation methods.
- * Learned and completed the probabilistic modeling of magnetic-inertial sensor measuring process.
- * Implemented the constrained extended Kalman filter (CEKF) to fuse a constant velocity model and magnetic-inertial sensor measurements to achieve pose estimation.
- * Defined the ambiguity issue in magnetic-inertial pose estimation system and proposed its identification method, to analyze and interpret the observability in this nonlinear system.

Outcome

- * Achieved millimeter-degree 6-DoF pose estimation accuracy in experiments.
- * Applied for one CN patent.

On Ambiguity in 6-DoF Magnetic Pose Estimation §

01/2022-Present

· Contribution:

- * Utilized the geometry of the special Euclidean group to decouple position and orientation in ambiguity issue.
- * Employed the numerical optimization method to tackle the non-linearity in magnetic field distribution.

- * Systematized the framework to analyze the ambiguity issue in magnetic pose estimation systems, including its definition, categorization, identification algorithms and impact on pose estimation.
- * Proposed the optimal magnetic source design in magnetic pose estimation system to achieve 6-DoF pose estimation without ambiguity.
- * Derived the equation describing the dynamical nature of ambiguity issue.
- * Designed and conducted experiments to verify the framework and the performance of the optimal system.

· Outcome:

- * Achieved millimeter-degree-accuracy and unambiguous 6-DoF pose estimation with the prototype.
- * Submitted one manuscript to International Journal of Robotics Research, under the second-round review.
- * Earned recognition and funding through the Chinese National Training Program of Innovation and Entrepreneurship for Undergraduates, with a total funding amount of \$1300.

RELATED COURSE PROJECTS

Tendon-Driven and Flex Sensor Based Gesture Sensing Hand Exoskeleton 🚱 | Team Leader Spring 2023

- 10 motors are controlled to stretch tendons attached to the hand exoskeleton, achieving independent control of all five fingers. Moreover, flex sensors are fixed with fingers to measure their bending extent, providing gesture information, to construct the closed-loop gesture control of fingers.
- **Key words:** PID Motor Control, 3D Modeling and Manufacturing of Exoskeleton, Tendon-driven Mechanism, Bending Sensor, Closed-loop Gesture Tracking.

Wireless-Powered Animation System Displayed by Rotating LEDs 🔗 | Team Leader Fall 2022

- Multiple embedded system modules, motor-driving, infrared-monitoring, wireless-charging and sounding-effect, were controlled to present the **self-designed animation** based on the principle of persistence of vision.
- **Key words:** Wireless-charging Coil & Circuit Design, Infrared Sensor, Sounding Module, Animation Presented by Rotating LED Stripe.

Omni-Motion, Bluetooth-control and Self-Reloading Automatic Catapult & Team Leader Spring 2022

- The **kinematic model** of the 4 omni-wheel motion was analyzed to achieve the **omni-direction control**. Remote operation was achieved using the **Bluetooth** device and **one self-designed android app**. Moreover, a self-reloading mechatronics device was developed by **3D printing**, **laser cutting and circuit design** technologies.
- **Key words:** Omni-motion UGV Design and Manufacturing, Bluetooth Module & Android App, Self-reloading Mechanism, Lever-Spring-Motor Shooting Mechanism.

Machine Learning & IMU Based Classifier on Ping-Pong Players' Motion 6 Team Leader Fall 2021

- Neural network and decision tree classifiers were ensembled to distinguish the motion of forehand drive and backhand stroke of a Ping-Pong player based on the inertial data. Moreover, One-class SVM and Local outlier factor were employed to detect wrong motions during training which may bring damage to the player's wrist.
- **Key words:** Inertial Sensor, Classifier: Neural Network & Decision Tree, Fault Detection: One-class SVM & Local Outlier Factor, Ping-Pong Training Monitoring.

Selected Awards & Honors •

| Mathematical Contest in Modeling | 05/2023 |
|---|---------|
| Honorable Mention (Second-Class Award), Top 30% | |
| Alibaba Cloud Programming Contest in SCUT | 03/2023 |
| Third-Class Award, Top 15% | |
| Undergraduate Internship Scholarship, China Scholarship Council & University of Alberta | 08/2022 |
| Only 1 in South China University of Technology and total 9 in China | |
| National Contest on Micro Sensing and Intelligent Technology | 10/2021 |
| National First Prize & Excellent Defense, Top 4% | |

SKILLS

Languages: Chinese (Native), English (IELTS: 7.0/9.0) **Programming**: MATLAB & Simulink, Python, C, C++, R

Others: ROS2, SolidWorks, Embedded System Development, Photo & Video Editing, LaTeX & Markdown